<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!--**********************************************************
Copyright 2021  All Rights Reserved
Robert A. Beezer, David W. Farmer, Alex Jordan

This file is used by the PreTeXt project to track projects
authored and distributed with PreTeXt.  By contributing edits,
or new project files, you agree to transfer your copyright
interest to the individuals named above.
***********************************************************-->

<!-- ########### -->
<!-- Version   2 -->
<!-- ########### -->

<project xml:id="branson-george-MFTP" updated="2021-03-02">
    <title>Math for the People</title>
    <author>
        <displayname>Mark Branson</displayname>
        <affiliation>Stevenson University</affiliation>
    </author>
    <author>
        <displayname>Whitney George</displayname>
        <affiliation>University of Wisconsin La Crosse</affiliation>
    </author>
    <license
        code="undecided"
        variant=""
        version="" 
        pub-year=""
        price=""
        />
    <character 
        subject="math"
        level="ugld"
        phase="develop"
        />
    <sites
        landing=""
        source="https://web.stevenson.edu/mbranson/math-for-the-people.xml"
        html="https://web.stevenson.edu/mbranson/math-for-the-people.html"
        pdf=""
        print=""
        />
    <description>
        <p>
            The text will be structured in stand-alone modules, each related to a single social justice topic.
            Each module will begin with an overview of the topic, historical context,
            and a discussion of current questions and concerns related to the topic.
            This section may include particular case studies related to the topic,
            articles discussing the topic, and other resources.
            This section will followed by discussion prompts for faculty to use in helping students explore the issue.
        </p>
        <p>
            The mathematical content will follow.
            Each topic will be paired with 2<ndash/>4 mathematical topics
            which will help the reader to ask questions and build understanding about the social justice topic being discussed.
            These mathematical topic sections will stand alone, and may be repeated in multiple places throughout the text
            (for example, a section on exponential growth may be included in the module on climate change
            as well as the module on predatory lending).
        </p>
        <p>
            Each module will end with homework exercises related to the social justice and mathematics topics,
            longer prompts intended to support more extensive explorations of the topics,
            and reflection questions to encourage students to consider what they’ve learned.
        </p>
    </description>

    <onesentence>
        <pubtitle>Math for the People</pubtitle>is a revolutionary new textbook<mdash/>with an emphasis on the revolution<mdash/>which teaches quantitative reasoning skills through social justice topics.
    </onesentence>

    <features
        hints="no"
        answers="no"
        solutions="no"
        reading-questions="no"
        webwork="no"
        videos="no"
        worksheets="no"
        projects="no"
        accessible="no"
        self-study="no"
        instructor-solutions="no"
        instructor-guide="no"
        test-bank="no"
        />
    <recognition
        aim="no"
        />
    <awards>
    </awards>
</project>